RG 079:003, Board of Fisheries and Game
Connecticut State Library
Board of Fisheries and Game records
1911-1990
bulk 1934-1957
Connecticut State Library
Connecticut. State Board of Fisheries and Game
6.5 cubic feet
In 1895 the Fish Commissioners became the Commissioners of Fisheries and Game charged with "the supervision of hatcheries and retaining ponds, the introduction and distribution of such food fish and game as are adapted to the waters or lands of this State, and the enforcement of all laws relating to fish and game." The Commission became the State Board of Fisheries and Game in 1913.
RG079_003
Historical Note
Fish Commissioners were established in 1867 per Public Acts chpt. 111. In 1895 the name was changed to Commissioners of Fisheries and Game per Public Acts chpt. 46. The Commission was charged with "the supervision of hatcheries and retaining ponds, the introduction and distribution of such food fish and game as are adapted to the waters or lands of this State, and the enforcement of all laws relating to fish and game."1 The name changed again in 1914 to State Board of Fisheries and Game per Public Acts chpt. 228. This Act provided for the appointment of a superintendent of fisheries and game who in turn appointed a fish and game warden from each county. Fish and game wardens would have the power to arrest for the violation of any law relating to fish and game.2 In 1971 the Board merged into the new Department of Environmental Protection.
See also the.
Endnotes
1First Biennial Report of the Commission of Fisheries and Game of the State of Connecticut, For the Fiscal Years 1895-1896. Hartford, Conn.: Fowler & Miller Co., 1896.
2Connecticut Fish & Game Laws, In Force November 1, 1913. Hartford, Conn., 1913.
Scope and Content
Case files contain warden's case reports and complaint forms, as well as notification to towns regarding prohibitions on licenses, correspondence, and prohibition appeals. Correspondence includes press releases, public relations schedules, memos, statistical information and reports on various subject. Warden's files contain personnel files for for Ray M. Brittingham, Walter S. Watson, Charles R. Disbrow, and Edith A. Stoehr, the first female game warden in the United States. These records are restricted. Minutes contain files only from 1956. Photographs are primarily black and white and include warden activities such as predator control, game breeding, conservation activities, warden training and state lands. Many are mounted on acidic cardboard. A small number of photographs were added from the Law Enforcement Unit of the Dept. of Environmental Protection which assumed many of the Board's responsibilities in 1971.
Arrangement
Case files, 1949-1957
Accession: 1992-080, 1949-1955, 3 cubic feet
Accession: 2000-017, 1956-1957, 1 cubic foot
Correspondence, 1952-1954, Accession: 1993-136 (part), 1.25 cubic feet
Warden's Files, 1934-1946, Accession: 1993-146, 0.25 cubic feet
Minutes, 1956, Accession: 1993-135 (part), 0.5 cubic feet
Photographs, 1911-1990, Accession: 1993-135 (part), 0.5 cubic feet
Related Material
RG 079:016, Department of Environmental Protection: Natural Resources and Outdoor Recreation. The Law Enforcement Unit records include arrest cards for 1940-1978, the bulk of which came from the Board of Fisheries and Game.
Index Terms
Organizations:
Connecticut. Dept. of Environmental Protection; Connecticut. State Board of Fisheries and Game
Subjects:
Connecticut. State Board of Fisheries and Game -- Records and correspondence; Fisheries -- Connecticut; Game protection-- Connecticut; Game wardens-- Connecticut; Wildlife conservation-- Connecticut; Wildlife management -- Connecticut
Document Types:
Correspondence; Minutes; Photographs; Reports
Restrictions on Access
These records are stored at an off-site facility and therefore may not be available on a same-day basis.
See the policy.
Container List
- Case Files, 1949-1957
  Arranged by fiscal year.
  There is no "R" series, 1955-1956.
  - 1992-080
    - "L" Series, 1949-1950
      - Litchfield - District I (Box 1)
      - Hartford - District II (Box 1)
      - New Haven - District III (Box 1)
      - Fairfield - District IV (Box 1)
      - Tolland - District V (Box 1)
      - Windham - District VII (Box 1)
      - Windham - District VI (Box 1)
      - New London - District VII (Box 1)
      - Middlesex - District VIII (Box 1)
    - "M" Series, 1950-1951 (Box 1)
      - Litchfield - District I (Box 1)
      - Hartford - District II (Box 1)
      - New Haven - District III (Box 1)
      - Fairfield - District IV (Box 1)
      - Tolland - District V (Box 1)
      - Windham - District VII (Box 1)
      - Windham - District VI (Box 1)
      - New London - District VII (Box 1)
      - Middlesex - District VIII (Box 1)
      - Marine (Box 1)
    - "N" Series, 1951-1952 (Box 1)
      - Litchfield - District I (Box 1)
      - Hartford - District II (Box 1)
      - New Haven - District III (Box 1)
      - Fairfield - District IV (Box 1)
      - Tolland - District V (Box 1)
      - Windham - District VII (Box 1)
      - Windham - District VI (Box 1)
      - New London - District VII (Box 1)
      - Middlesex - District VIII (Box 1)
      - Marine (Box 1)
    - "O" Series, 1952-1953 (Box 2)
      - Litchfield - District I (Box 2)
      - Hartford - District II (Box 2)
      - New Haven - District III (Box 2)
      - Fairfield - District IV (Box 2)
      - Tolland - District V (Box 2)
      - Windham - District VII (Box 2)
      - Windham - District VI (Box 2)
      - New London - District VII (Box 2)
      - Middlesex - District VIII (Box 2)
      - Marine (Box 2)
    - "P" Series, 1953-1954 (Box 2)
      - Litchfield - District I, 2 folders (Box 2)
      - Hartford - District II (Box 2)
      - New Haven - District III (Box 2)
      - Fairfield - District IV (Box 2)
      - Tolland - District V (Box 2)
      - Windham - District VII (Box 2)
      - Windham - District VI (Box 2)
      - New London - District VII (Box 2)
      - Middlesex - District VIII (Box 2)
    - "Q" Series, 1954-1955 (Box 3)
      - District I (Box 3)
      - District II (Box 3)
      - District III (Box 3)
      - District IV (Box 3)
  - 2000-017
    - "S" Series, 1956-1957 (Box 1)
      - District I, 2 folders (Box 1)
      - District II (Box 1)
      - District III (Box 1)
      - District IV (Box 1)
- Correspondence, 1952-1954; 1993-136 (part)
  Part of this accession is correspondence from the Law Enforcement Division, the successor to Board of Fisheries and Game, and is described in the finding aid for Natural Resources and Outdoor Recreation.
  - Attorney General (Box 1)
  - Auditors (Box 1)
  - Civil Defense (Box 1)
  - Education, Board of (Box 1)
  - Finance & Control (Box 1)
  - Food & Drug (Box 1)
  - Governor's Office (Box 1)
  - Health Dept. (Box 1)
  - Highway Dept. (Box 1)
  - Labor Dept. (Box 1)
  - Library Dept. (Box 1)
  - Military Dept. (Box 1)
  - Montgomery, Hon John D. (Box 1)
  - Moss, D., Supvr. of Fish Man. (Box 1)
  - Norling, Roger (Box 1)
  - Park & Forest Dept. (Box 1)
  - Personnel Correspondence (Box 1)
  - Personnel General Letters (Box 1)
  - Police Dept. (Box 1)
  - Public Works Dept. (Box 1)
  - Purchasing Dept. Contracts, 1952-1954 (Box 1)
  - Purchasing Dept. Correspondence (Box 1)
  - Purchasing Dept. General Requisitions (Box 1)
  - Purchasing Div. Memos/General Letters (Box 1)
  - Retirement (Box 1)
  - Secretary of State (Box 1)
  - Shellfish Commission (Box 1)
  - Treasurer's Office (Box 1)
  - Water Commission (Box 1)
  - MOA - MON (Box 1)
  - MI - MN (Box 1)
  - MOO - MQ (Box 1)
  - MR - MX (Box 1)
  - MY - MZ (Box 1)
  - NA - NH (Box 1)
  - NI - NN (Box 1)
  - NO - NZ (Box 1)
  - OA - OD (Box 1)
  - OE -ON (Box 1)
  - PA - PD (Box 2)
  - PE (Box 2)
  - PF - PK (Box 2)
  - PL - PQ (Box 2)
  - PR - PX (Box 2)
  - PY - Q (Box 2)
- Warden's Files, 1934-1946; 1993-146
  RESTRICTED
  Personnel files for Ray M. Brittingham, Walter S. Watson, Charles R. Disbrow, and Edith A. Stoehr, the first female game warden in the United States.
- Minutes, 1956; 1993-135 (part)
  - Minutes, 1956; 9 folders (Box 1)
- Photographs, 1911-1990; 1993-135 (part)
  - Animals, 1933, undated (Box 1)
  - Archery event, 1928 (Box 1)
  - ATV going through a park in Middletown, no trespassing zone, 1988 (Box 1)
  - Birds and birds' nests, 1933, undated (Box 1)
  - Bride Lake, 1932, 1935 (Box 1)
  - Civilian Conservation Corps, undated (Box 1)
  - Commercial game breeders, 1932-1936 (Box 1)
  - Conservation officer graduation MPTC and canine officer training MPTC Officer of the Year Award, 1982, 1984 (Box 1)
  - Conservation officers, 1938, circa 1990 (Box 1)
  - Conservation officer "surveillance", circa 1980 (Box 1)
  - Cromwell Meadows, 1932-1934 (Box 1)
  - Deer, undated (Box 1)
  - Dogs, undated (Box 1)
  - Drought conditions on Blackledge River, undated (Box 1)
  - Ducks, 1932-1936, undated (Box 1)
  - Exclusive fishing rights, 1971 (Box 1)
  - Field day outing, 1928 (Box 1)
  - First female game warden, undated (Box 1)
  - Fishers Island, undated (Box 1)
  - Fishing, 1934, undated (Box 1)
  - Hatcheries - shad, 1929 (Box 1)
  - Hunting pictures - men, 1934, undated (Box 1)
  - Leased or regulated shooting areas, 1934, undated (Box 1)
  - Litchfield Morris Sanctuary, 1934, 1936, undated (Box 1)
  - Lobster case, 1978 (Box 1)
  - Lord's Cove, 1932, 1934, undated (Box 1)
  - Muskrat, undated (Box 1)
  - Pheasant liberations, 1932-1935, undated (Box 1)
  - Predator control, 1926, 1932-1936, undated (Box 1)
  - Quail and grouse experiment, Storrs, 1911 (Box 1)
  - Raccoon, 1932, undated (Box 1)
  - Smokey Bear visits Gay City State Park, 1987 (Box 1)
  - State Forests, 1934, circa 1970-1979, undated (Box 1)
  - Typical game covers, 1934-1935, undated (Box 1)
  - Violations, 1925, 1930, 1933, undated (Box 1)
  - Warden meeting, undated (Box 1)
  - Warden school, 1937 (Box 1)
  - Wild rice, 1932-1933, 1935, undated (Box 1)
  - Winter feeding of birds, 1933-1934, undated (Box 1)
  - Woman's shooting ground, 1936, undated (Box 1)
  - Miscellaneous, 1927-1936 (Box 1)